Guide to the Thornton Wilder Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Thornton Wilder collection
1918-1983
YCAL MSS 162
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
11.67
(16 boxes)
The collection consists of letters, manuscripts and other publication material, and other papers related to Thornton Wilder. Included are extensive letters to his close friends Amy Wertheimer and William Layton; letters of literary advice to Joe Etta Lee Clarke and Hester Pickman; and materials concerning his publicist, Lee Keedick, and his publisher, Harper and Row.
Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Thornton Wilder Collection was acquired through gifts and purchases from various non-Wilder family sources to complement the Thornton Wilder Papers (YCAL MSS 108).
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Restricted Fragile in boxes 14-15 may only be consulted with permission of the appropriate curator. Preservation photocopies or photographic prints for reference use have been substituted in the main files.
Associated Materials
For manuscript material related to Thornton Wilder donated by Wilder and members of the Wilder family, see the Thornton Wilder Papers, YCAL MSS 108.
THORNTON WILDER (1897-1975)
A biographical timeline is provided in the register for the Thornton Wilder Papers (YCAL MSS 108).
Scope and Contents
The Thornton Wilder Collection consists of letters, manuscripts and publication material, and other papers by and concerning Thornton Wilder. The collection spans the dates 1918-1983.
The collection is housed in 15 boxes and consists of ten series: Joe Etta Lee Clarke Estate Gift; Harper and Row Gift; Amy Wertheimer Papers; Joseph W. Still Gift; Foresman/Tibby Family Papers; Inez Peck Kashman Bequest; Lee Keedick Papers; Wiliam Layton Papers; Hester Pickman Correspondence; Materials from Other Sources.
Series I, Joe Etta Lee Clarke Estate Gift, is organized into two subseries: Letters from Thornton Wilder and Writings of Joe Etta Lee Clarke. Folders 1-8 contain chronologically arranged letters from Wilder to Clarke, mostly concerning suggestions for and publication prospects for the unpublished novel "Sheba House," the manuscript of which is located in folders 9-20.
Series II, Harper and Row Gift, is organized into subseries by title. Contents include galley proofs, page proofs, and errata lists; and the holograph draft of Wilder's Preface to the 1957 Three Plays. An "author's information sheet" incompletely filled out by Wilder contains his note to the publicity department: "Sorry---dont seem to be any use at this. TW." Material related to adaptations of Our Town for possible radio and television serialization is located in folders 29-42 and includes typescripts of sample episodes and comments by Isabel Wilder.
Series III, Amy Wertheimer Papers, is housed in Box 3 and consists almost entirely of letters from Thornton Wilder to Wertheimer. The two met in the summer of 1925 at Lake Sunapee, and in October of that year Wilder described their friendship as it seemed to him: "I am looking for a wise, intelligent and fairly tranquil friend. I should like it to be a lady, somewhat older than myself...." For the next two years, Wilder's frequent and lengthy letters stress the limits of their relationship and remind Wertheimer of them: "You must accept the conditions of life as things are. 1. I have never implied that I could love you." Wilder repeatedly dissuaded Westheimer from meeting him in what he considered socially compromising situations, discouraged her thoughts of divorce, and finally, in March of 1927, ended this phase of the correspondence: "I asked for a year's pause....I am much too fond of you to go thru the trials of another meeting like that Central Park one."
The remainder of the letters are filled with affectionate tributes to Westheimer as a "tower of strength" for him; news of his family, his travels, and his difficulties in writing; advice on family matters, and sympathetic and frank comments on their experiences with depression and "dark nights of the soul." In a June, 1937 letter Wilder reminds her that "The problem of living is to make a solitude that is not a loneliness" and that she is important to many. The letters of the late 1930s and 1940s contain description of his work on "Our Town" and "The Skin of Our Teeth" and of productions of these.
Series IV, Joseph W. Still Gift, is housed in Box 4, folders 67-76. The letters of the 1940s are principally concerned with the war and in particular with Still's work on planning for the future Allied occupation of Nazi Germany. Folder 68 contains a copy of his "Population Dynamics and the Problem of Planning a Lasting Peace." His report, which envisaged long-term strict control of Germany's educational system and media, drew a sharp dissent from Wilder, whose own manuscript outlines "The Wilder Plan" in contrast to "The Still Plan." For example, Wilder rejects the widely accepted faith in long-term censorship: "a gradual relaxing of supervision is necessary [in order to] see what trends appear. German attitudes should not be driven underground." Other subjects include Still's later scientific career; Wilder's works and family news; and descriptions of travel plans.
Series V, Foresman/Tibby Family Papers, consists of letters from Wilder to members of the Foresman and Tibby families. Edwin Clyde Foresman was master of Davis House at Lawrenceville, and Wilder succeeded him after his death in 1927. His correspondence with the Foresmans, both Clyde and Grace, is located in folders 77-82 and contains discussion of the last illness of Clyde; personal news; travel plans; and Davis House affairs. The two 1967 letters concern Grace Foresman's reaction to The Eighth Day and Wilder's comments on his "tribute--in reverse " to the Foresmans in the "St. Kitts" section of that novel.
Wilder also remained in touch with the Foremans' daughter Emily and her husband John Tibby. His 1935 letters contain advice concerning her mother and encouragement about her play, "The Big Town." The 1967 letters addressed to John Kerr Tibby offer analyses of Tibby's character and marriages.
Series V also contains a typescript carbon of a 1922 Wilder essay on the poet Shelley, which he apparently sent to Emily Foresman in 1934; and a family history of the Foresmans and Tibbys by John Kerr Tibby.
Series VI, Inez Peck Kashman Bequest, is housed in folders 88-92 and contains letters from Wilder to "Inez and Bill" concerning his health and his travel plans; newspaper clippings about Wilder; and photographs of Wilder from a 1966 visit with the Kashmans.
Series VII, Lee Keedick Papers, is located in Box 5. The correspondence, consisting of originals from Wilder to Keedick and office file carbons of Keedick's replies, spans the dates 1928-1939 and documents the details of several lecture tours for which Keedick was Wilder's agent and promoter. After the 1927 success of The Bridge of San Luis Rey, Wilder was in demand as a lecturer, and much information on his appearances and popular reaction can be found in the 1928-29 letters, located in folders 93-101.
Wilder gradually reduced the number of his public appearances throughout the 1930s, a change reflected in the Keedick letters, and the correspondence ends in November 1939 with Wilder's refusal of another tour: "I'd love the towns and hotels and trains--if there were no lectures."
The series also contains newspaper clippings and printed material concerning Wilder's work, and folder 117 holds copies of Keedick's publicity flyers for Wilder's lectures.
Series VIII, William Layton Papers, is housed in Box 6 and consists almost entirely of letters written to Layton by Wilder during the 1940s and early 1950s. Topics include military work and Wilder's views of World War II; details of productions of Wilder's plays, with commentary on staging and on Tallulah Bankhead; Layton's own interest in acting and directing; and news of mutual friends and Wilder's travel plans.
Series IX, Hester Pickman Papers, consists of two versions of "Circe's Isle" by Hester Pickman and one folder of correspondence about Wilder's suggestions and his own interpretation of the Circe myth.
Series X, Materials from Other Sources, has been organized into three subseries: Letters by Thornton Wilder; Other Correspondence; and Writings and Other Papers. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically by correspondent or by title of work. Letters by Thornton Wilder contains single letters or small groups of letters: recipients include Kendall Bragg, Clyde Lasswell, Seymour Lawrence, Sol Lesser, Marcia Nardi, and Jack E. Reynolds.
Folders 147-148 hold letters to the columnist Leonard Lyons; subjects include comments about the columns and Wilder's promises to contribute material; Wilder's opinions of actors and other Broadway figures; and a Dorothy Parker anecdote. Wilder's letters to Bruce Simonds, located in folders 160-162, contain comments on music, Wilder's works, the marriage of Simonds and Rosalind Brown Simonds, and are accompanied by annotated typescripts of two "Three Minute Plays for Three Persons."
Wilder's 1926-1927 correspondence with the Townsons provides many details of his employment as Andrew Townson's tutor during a European tour, as well as Wilder's attempts to suggest further educational avenues for him.
The Writings subseries includes a typescript carbon of the script for "Shadow of a Doubt;" a corrected typescript carbon of the first "Our Town" script; and a holograph draft of a Wilder lecture on Thoreau. Accessions since 1997 of individual items and small groups of material related to Wilder are listed in order of acquisition at the end of the series.
Oversize material is housed in boxes 10-13. Restricted Fragile material is housed in boxes 14-15.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Denazification; Authors; Bragg, Kendall; Clarke, Joe Etta Lee; Keedick, Lee; Layton, William; Lyons, Leonard; Pickman, Hester; Simonds, Bruce; Still, Joseph William; Wertheimer, Amy; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975; Harper & Row, Publishers
- Estate of Joe Etta Lee Clarke Gift, 1935-1949; Series I; 0.41; (1 box)
  Scope and Contents
  Gift of the Estate of Joe Etta Lee Clarke, 1966
  - LETTERS FROM THORNTON WILDER
    - Correspondence, 1935-49 (Box 1, Folder 1-8)
  - WRITINGS OF JOE ETTA LEE CLARKE
    - "Sheba House"
      - Notes, holograph and typescript (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
      - Typescript, annotated by Clarke, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11-20)
- Harper and Row Gift, 1934-1968; Series II; 0.41; (1 box)
  Gift of Harper and Row, 1972
  - THE CABALA
    - Book IV: typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - THE CABALA AND THE WOMAN OF ANDROS (HARPER AND ROW, 1968)
    - Setting copy: typescript, corrected, marked, of Preface and opening pages, [1968] (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Setting copy: 1928 printing of The Cabala, cut and marked (Box 2, Folder 23-24)
    - Setting copy: 1930 printing of The Woman of Andros, cut and marked (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
    - Galley proofs of Harper edition of The Cabala and The Woman of Andros, corrected, 1968
    - Page proofs of Harper edition of The Cabala and the Woman of Andros, corrected, 1968
  - HEAVEN'S MY DESTINATION
    - Author's Information Sheet: printed publicity form completed by TW, 1934 Nov 22 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - THE IDES OF MARCH
    - Errata lists: holograph manuscript and typescript carbon, annotated, 1948, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - OUR TOWN
    - Correspondence relating to proposed radio series based on Our Town, 1941-44, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Notes on characters for proposed series: typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - "General outline of the first 13 episodes:" typsescript carbon, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - With notes by IW on "Definite points," typescript carbon
    - Typescript carbon, corrected and annotated by IW, of draft radio scripts and incomplete draft radio scripts (Box 2, Folder 32-37)
    - "Audition Episode No. 1:" typescriptx carbon, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 38)
      With synopses of proposed episodes
    - "Audition 1:" mimeograph, annotated by IW, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - "Audition 2:" mimeograph, annotated by IW, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - "Television 10-minute version:" typescript carbon, corrected and annotated (Box 2, Folder 41)
      Note by IW: "Given on Showtime Sunday evening 7:30 New York-- May 6--'51"
    - "An Episode for television designed as one of a series:" typescript carbon, 1950 May (Box 2, Folder 42)
      By Jerome Ross
      Material apparently submitted to the publisher through Brandt & Brandt
  - THREE PLAYS (HARPER & ROW, 1957)
    - "Preface:" holograph manuscript, corrected and signed, 1957, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Amy Wertheimer Papers, 1925-1969; Series III; 0.41; (1 box)
  Purchased from Nancy Kleinbrod, 1981
  Acc. 19810610-a
  - Correspondence, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 45-48)
  - Correspondence, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - 2 ALS to Alfred Wertheimer, 1927 Dec (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    With ALS to Thornton Wilder from Marie Belloc Lowndes, [1928] Aug 21
    With ALS to Thornton Wilder from Cecilia Beaux, [1928?] Jul 5
    With ALS to Thornton Wilder from H. D., [1928?] "Friday"
  - Correspondence, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    With ALS to Thornton Wilder from Laura Kamlah, 1929 Jul 14
  - Correspondence, 1930-31 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence, 1933-34 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence, 1935-36 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence, 1940-42 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Correspondence, 1943-45 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence, 1948-51 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Correspondence, 1952-57 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Correspondence, 1958-68 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Correspondence, 1969, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Notes and other papers, 1934-46, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 66)
- Joseph W. Still Gift, 1943-1975; Series IV; 0.2; (.5 box)
  Gift of Joseph W. Still, 1982
  - Correspondence, 1943-45 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    With photograph of residents of Ellice Island, 1943
  - Corrrespondence, [ca. 1944-45] (Box 4, Folder 68)
    With typescript carbon, corrected, of "Population Dynamics and the Problem of Planning a Lasting Peace," n.d., with population chart; and holograph manuscript by TW, untitled, outlining his analysis of the "Still plan" and "The Wilder Plan" for postwar German education and rehabilitation.
    With holograph manuscript of TW's "Metellus to Caesar," n.d.
  - Correspondence, 1946-47 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    With typescript carbon of sheep research proposal, n.d.
  - Correspondence, 1948-49 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Correspondence, 1951-52 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    With photograph of TW encl. 1952 Nov 20. Annotated in TW's hand: "Decrepitude. Venice. Case history No. 346"
  - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    With typescript carbon, annotated, of "The Fallacy of Opposites," by Still
  - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Correspondence, 1955-56 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Correspondence, 1957-58 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    With ANS by Still concerning lack of correspondence 1959-69 and newspaper clipping, n.d.
  - Correspondence, 1970-75 (Box 4, Folder 76)
- Foresman/Tibby Family Papers, 1922-1982; Series V; 10
  Gift of John K. M. Tibby, 1982
  - TW LETTERS TO MR. AND MRS. EDWIN CLYDE FORESMAN
    - Correspondence, 1922-26 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Correspondence, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 78-79)
    - Correspondence, 1929-34 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Correspondence, 1935-37 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Correspondence, 1967 Apr, Aug (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - TW LETTERS TO EMILY FORESMAN TIBBY AND JOHN TIBBY
    - Corrrespondence, 1935-38 (Box 4, Folder 83)
      With typescript, annotated, signed, of "The Big Town" by Emily Foresman
    - Correspondence, 1943, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Correspondence, 1967 May-Aug (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Correspondence, 1969-74, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - WRITINGS
    - Typescript carbon of essay by TW on Shelley: written for an exhibit of Shelley material at the Brick Row Book Store, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 87)
      With typescript ownership history and family history by John Tibby, 1982
- Inez Peck Kashman Bequest, 1966-1983; Series VI; 5
  Bequest of Inez Peck Kashman (Mrs. William Cashman), 1985
  - Correspondence, 1966-74, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Acknowledgement of sympathy card, 1976 Jan 6 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    With ANS from Isabel Wilder
  - Newspaper clippings, 1967-83, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - 2 photographs of Thornton Wilder, [1966] (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - 4 color slides of Thornton Wilder, [1966] (Box 4, Folder 92)
- Lee Keedick Papers, 1928-1939; Series VII; 0.21; (1 box)
  Purchased from Argosy Book Store on the Thornton Wilder Fund, 1992
  - CORRESPONDENCE WITH TW
    - Correspondence, 1928-29 (Box 5, Folder 93-101)
    - Correspondence, 1930-34 (Box 5, Folder 102-107)
    - Correspondence, 1935-39 (Box 5, Folder 108-112)
  - WRITINGS OF TW
    - The Bridge of San Luis Rey
      - Newspaper clippings, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - Our Town
      - Advertisement for Coward-McCann publication, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 114)
      - Program, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 115)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1937-38 (Box 5, Folder 116)
  - OTHER PAPERS
    - Publicity flyers for TW as lecturer, [1927, 1930] (Box 5, Folder 117)
    - Obituary of Amos P. Wilder: newspaper clipping, 1936 Jul 3 (Box 5, Folder 118)
- William Layton Papers, 1942-1973; Series VIII; 0.14; (.75 box)
  Purchased from William Layton on the Thornton Wilder and Donald Windham Funds, 1993.
  - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 119)
  - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 120-121)
  - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 122)
  - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 123)
  - Corrrespondence, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 124-125)
  - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 126)
  - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 127-128)
  - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 129)
  - Correspondence, 1950-53 (Box 6, Folder 130)
  - Correspondence, 1957-73 (Box 6, Folder 131)
- Hester Pickman Papers, 1955-1956; Series IX; 0.06; (.25 box)
  Purchased from Serendipity Books on the Thornton Wilder Fund, 1999
  - Correspondence, 1955-56 (Box 6, Folder 132)
    With TLS to Hester Pickman from "Teddy" [Theodore Chanler], 1956 Feb 27, enclosing TLS from TW to Chanler, n.d.
  - Holograph manuscript and revisions of "Circe's Isle", in hand of Hester Pickman, [1956?] (Box 6, Folder 133-134)
  - Typescripts, carbon, annotated, of "Circe's Isle," "2nd version" (Box 6, Folder 135-136)
- Materials from Other Sources, 1918-1975; Series X; 0.84; (3 boxes)
  Acquired from various sources. For further information, see accession records for individual items.
  - LETTERS BY THORNTON WILDER
    - 2 ALS to Kendall Bragg, 1929, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 137)
      With page of Bragg's appointment book recording meeting with Wilder, 1931 Feb 21
      Accompanied by: TL carbon from Frances Bragg to Amos Wilder, 1985 Jun 3; and TLS from AW to Frances Bragg, 1985 Jun 5
      Acc: 19910128-d
    - ALS to Frank Brieff; Hamden, [1968 Aug 16] (Box 7, Folder 138)
      With envelope
      Acc: 19980507-a
    - 2 ALS to Frank Brieff; hamden, 1961, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 139)
      Acc: 19980529-h
    - ALS to Hamilton Holt; Century Club, New York, 1931 Sep 23 (Box 7, Folder 140)
      Accompanied by typed transcript.
      Acc: 19850111 (?)
    - ALS to Michael Horowitz; Hamden, 1962 Feb 7 (Box 7, Folder 141)
      Acc: 19960426-c
    - Letters to Rose Jackson [Mrs. John Day Jackson], 1942-67, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 142)
      With photograph of Thornton Wilder, Gertrude Stein, Alice B. Toklas, and others
      With 3 envelopes
      Acc: 19810903
    - 2 ALS to Clyde Lasswell; London and Hamden, 1954, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 143)
      With ALS from Isabel Wilder to Clyde Lasswell; Hamden, 1965 Nov 12
      Acc: 19880627-a
    - 8 ALS and 5 APCS to Seymour Lawrence, 1952-64, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 144)
      Acc: 19890203-f
    - 2 ALS to Fay Lesser; Hamden, 1942, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 145)
      With envelopes
      Acc: 19830729
    - APCS to Sol Lesser; Boston, 1967 Jun 1 (Box 7, Folder 146)
    - 21 ALS and APCS to Leonard Lyons, 1942-68, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 147-148)
      With 9 envelopes
      Acc: 19990429-a
    - 4 ALS to Miriam Mermey, 1941-48, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 149)
      Acc: 20000831-p
    - APCS to Guy Métraux; Cambridge, 1951 Apr 18 (Box 7, Folder 150)
      Acc: 198008-
    - ALS to Marcia Nardi; Hamden, 1972 Mar 28 (Box 7, Folder 151)
      Acc: 19820504
    - 5 ALS to Daisy Newman; Hamden, 1956-75 (Box 7, Folder 152)
      With 2 envelopes
      Acc: 19860115-b
    - 2 ALS to George and Irene Reavey; Peterborough, Hamden, 1953 Sep, Oct (Box 7, Folder 153)
      Acc: 19811218
    - ALS to Joseph Reed; Hamden, 1953 Jun 3 (Box 7, Folder 154)
      Acc: 19880107-a
    - 9 ALS to Jack E. Reynolds, 1937-52 (Box 7, Folder 155-158)
      With TL carbon from Reynolds to Wilder, 1968 Apr 10
      With newspaper clippings, 1968-89
      Acc: 19940819-a
    - 5 ALS to Samuel French, Inc., 1938-62 (Box 7, Folder 159)
      With 2 TLS from Isabel Wilder to Samuel French, Inc.; 1949, 1962
      Acc: 19960731-av
    - Letters to Bruce Simonds, 1918-47 (Box 7, Folder 160-162)
      With typescript of "And the Sea Shall Give Up Its Dead," annotated by Bruce Simonds; typescript of "Solvs inter deus potens," annotated, signed and dated by TW; and typescript, corrected by TW and annotated by Bruce Simonds, of a page of The Cabala.
      With ANS from Simonds to TW, n.d.
      Acc: 19901003-c
    - ALS to Jack Tibby; Hamden, 1950 Aug 15 (Box 7, Folder 163)
      With partial TLS from Tibby to H. W. Liebert
      Acc: 19820816
    - Letters to Douglas C. and Marie Townson, 1926-73 (Box 7, Folder 164-167)
      With enclosures concerning Andrew Townson, 1926-30, and typescripts, carbon, of letters concerning Andrew from Douglas Townson
      Acc: 19811222
    - ALS to Janet Camp Troxell; Hamden, 1950 Jun 28 (Box 7, Folder 168)
      Acc: 19890518-f
  - OTHER CORRESPONDENCE
    - Correspondence of Albert & Charles Boni with Wiggin & Dana and others, 1939-47 (Box 7, Folder 169-170)
      Concerning royalty offers
      Acc: 19770509-
    - Correspondence concerning Wilder's appearance on the Council for Democracy's radio program, 1941-42 (Box 7, Folder 171)
      Includes 4 ALS from Wilder to Rosemarie Griesser, as well as retained carbons of correspondence from the broadcast staff to Wilder and others
      Acc: 19940124-ad
    - 3 photographs of Thornton Wilder and other attendees at a dinner given by Helena Rubenstein; New York, [ca. 1938] (Box 7, Folder 172)
      Annotated with guest list by unidentified sender
      Acc: 19960726-f
  - WRITINGS AND OTHER PAPERS
    - Writings
      - The Angel that Troubled the Waters: dust jacket proof, corrected by TW, 1928
        Acc: 19560529
      - The Eighth Day: uncorrected galley proof, 1967
        Acc: 19890203-g
      - Heaven's My Destination: setting typescript, corrected, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 173-187)
        Acc: 19921001-a
      - Our Town: typescript carbon corrected, annotated, bound, [ca. 1938] (Box 9, Folder 188)
        Inscribed: "To Everett [Clinchy?] In memory of loggia days. Madge." in hand of TW
        Acc: 19871109-i
      - Shadow of a Doubt: typescript mimeograph, 1942 Jun-Jul (Box 9, Folder 189)
        Acc: 19911009-h
      - ["Thoreau"?]: holograph manuscript, corrected, marked, of a lecture on Henry David Thoreau given at Harvard (probably the Norton Lecture), 1952 Sep 9 (Box 9, Folder 190)
        Inscribed: "To George Hemphill. Regards of his friend Thornton Wilder. The MacDowell Colony, Peterboro, 9 Sept. 1952."
        Acc: 19991119-d